<?xml version="1.0" ?>
                   
<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
		version="5.0">
	<info>
      	<title>Quoddy Help</title>
		<author>
        	<personname>
        		<firstname>Phillip</firstname>
        		<surname>Rhodes</surname>
        	</personname>
		</author>
      	<copyright>
      		<year>2013</year>
      		<holder>Fogbeam Labs</holder>
      	</copyright>
	</info>	
	<chapter id="quoddyIntroChapter" xreflabel="Introduction to Quoddy" >
		
		<title>Introduction to Quoddy</title>
				
		<para>
			Quoddy is an Open Source Enterprise Social Network, which shares common "look and feel" elements, 
			and substantial functionality, with consumer facing Social Networks like 
			Facebook or Google+ as well as proprietary Enterprise Social Network products 
			like the products from Jive Software and Yammer among others.   But unlike
			consumer Social Networks, Quoddy is intended for organizational use and therefore has 
			capabilities which make it uniquely suited to provide the social fabric to 
			support organizational knowledge sharing, knowledge transfer, collaboration and 
			decision support.
		</para>

      	<section id="introActivityStreamSection" xreflabel="Activity Stream">
      	
      		<title>The Activity Stream</title>
			<para> The Activity Stream is the central element of the Quoddy interface.  The Activity Stream
				takes up the right hand side of the main page in Quoddy, and displays Status Updates
				from other users, Business Events from backend systems, Calendar Events from calendaring
				/ groupware systems, User Tasks from BPM / workflow systems, User activity events from external
				systems, Document links from Document Management Systems, and other events of interest to you, based on
				the users you friend/follow, groups you join, and the subscriptions you define. 
			</para>
	   		<para>
	   			Since Users do not necessarily want to see all content all the time, Quoddy has a concept known as
	   			Stream Definitions.  A User creates a Stream Definition to collect a related group of Users, User Lists, Groups
	   			and Subscriptions, and batch that content together.  When a User has multiple Stream Definitions, a simple
	   			dropdown menu allows the User to toggle which collection is rendered into the main Activity Stream at
	   			any given time.  
	   		</para>
	   	</section>		
		
		<section id="friendsSection" xreflabel="Friends &amp; Followers">
      	
      		<title>Friends &amp; Followers</title>
			<para> Adding another User as a "Friend" requires that User's approval and creates a two way
				connection between the two users.  Following a user creates a one-way connection and does not
				require approval from the user being followed. 
			</para>
			<para>
				By default, your <xref linkend="usingActivityStreamChapter"/> will be include Status Updates from users 
				who you have Friended or Followed.  In turn, Friended users, or users who Follow you, will receive
				your Status Updates by default.  However, configurable User Stream definitions in Quoddy allow you to fine
				tune your Activity Stream at a finer level of detail, to ensure that you receive exactly the information
				you need, and no more.  
			</para>

	   	
	   	</section>
		
		<section id="introUserListGroupSection" xreflabel="User Lists &amp; Groups">
      	
      		<title> User Lists &amp; Groups</title>
			<para> User Lists allow a User to group related people together, and quickly
				filter their Activity Stream down to only updates from those Users.  A User
				can have multiple such groups, and a simple dropdown menu allows the User to select
				the active User List at any time.
			</para>
	   		<para>
	   			Groups support multi-user collaboration around a given topic, interest, project, or other
	   			unifying concept.  Users may search for Groups which are of interest to them, join those
	   			Groups, and then share content with, and recieve status updates from, those Groups.  A User
	   			may join many Groups, and a simple dropdown menu allows the User to select which Group's content
	   			they wish to view at any given time.
	   		</para>
	   	</section>

		<section id="introSubscriptionSection" xreflabel="Subscriptions" >
      	
      		<title>Subscriptions</title>
			<para> 
				Perhaps the most powerful and important feature in Quoddy, subscriptions
				allow Users to register interest in various kinds of content from both within
				their organization, and from outside the organiation, and then have that content
				delivered straight to their Activity Stream.  
			</para>
	   		<para>
	   			Quoddy currently supports four types of Subscriptions:
	   			<itemizedlist mark='opencircle'>
					<listitem>
						Activiti User Tasks
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Business Events					
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Calendar Feeds
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						RSS Feed Subscription					
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
	   		</para>
	   		
	   		For more information on configuring Subscriptions please see the <xref linkend="subscriptionsChapter"/> chapter. 
	   	</section>
		
	</chapter>

	<chapter id="usingActivityStreamChapter" xreflabel="Activity Stream">
	
		<title>Using the Activity Stream</title>
		<section id="usingActivityStreamSection1">
		    <title>Basics</title>
			<para>
				Your Activity Stream will normally look something like the image below, filled with a variety of different
				types of content, including a mix of Status Updates from Friends, Calendar Events, Business Events and RSS Feed Items from 
				Subscriptions, etc. 
			</para>
			<imagedata fileref="images/activityStream1.png" width="550px" scalefit="1"/>
			<para>
				The Activity Stream area allows you to operate on this content in various ways, including:
				<itemizedlist mark="opencircle">
					<listitem>
						Commenting
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Voting
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						Sharing
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
			<para>
				Commenting provides a means to annotate content items with your personal observations, thoughts or insights, and
				to reply to similar comments from other users.  These discussions around a piece of content, such as a report from the
				Business Intelligence group, a Business Event, or other relevant enterprise content, facilitate the generation, capture
				and reuse of valuable knowledge and can directly lead to better decision making, increased productivity and crucial
				innovations. 
			</para>
			<para>
				To interact with the Comments on an item in your stream, simply click "Show Comments" to show any
				existing comments, or click inside the textbox labeled "Add a Comment" to leave your own comment.  To 
				temporarily hide the comments associated with an item, click  the "Hide Comments" link.
			</para>
			<para>
				To "Share" an item with another user, simply click the "Share" link near the bottom of the entry.  To add
				a comment to the newly shared item, add your comment text in the uppermost textbox of the resulting dialog.  Type the username
				of the user you are sharing the item with in the lower textbox and click "Submit" to complete the action.  Shared items
				will appear in the Activity Stream of the user you share with. 
			</para>
			<para>
			    (This feature is not yet implemented)
				To Vote (or "+1") an item in your stream, simply click the "+1" link at the bottom of the item, near the
				Comments area.  The current "score" of an item will reflect the number of users who have voted for it.  Voting
				also marks an item as being of interest to you, and - in future versions of Quoddy - will be factored into
				algorithms which automatically recommend content for you.  Future versions will also support the
				ability to quickly access the list of items that you have voted for, and the ability to remove an
				existing vote.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="usingActivityStreamSection2">
		    <title>User Stream Definitions</title>
		    <para>
		    	In order to provider users with fine-grained control over exactly which content appears in their Activity
		    	Stream, Quoddy supports the creation and user of user defined "Stream" entries which define a collection of
		    	requested content items by type, user, group, list, or subscription.  You may, for example, define a "Stream"
		    	which only includes Business Events and nothing else.  Or, you may define a Stream which includes content
		    	from three specifically designated users, plus events from a specific Calendar Feed, and Business
		    	Events from one specified Business Event Subscription.   You may mix and match and tailor these definitions
		    	to fit your exact criteria.
		    </para>
		    <para>
		    	The default Stream entry includes all content from all uses that you have friended or followed, as well
		    	as content from any Group you join, and all Subscriptions you create.  It is not recommended to
		    	modify the default Stream definition, but rather to create new definitions to suit your requirements.  The
		    	currently active Stream definition can be easily changed by selecting it from the "Streams" dropdown menu above
		    	the Activity Stream area.
		    </para>
		    <para>
		    	To create a new Stream definition, simply select the "Streams" dropdown menu, and click the "Manage Streams" lilnk, which will take
		    	you to a page that looks like the page below:
		    	<imagedata fileref="images/manageStreams1.png" width="550px" scalefit="1"/>
		    </para>
		  	<para>
		  		To continue creating your new Stream definition, click the big blue "Create a New Stream" button, which begins
		  		the New Stream Wizard.  The first page of the wizard will appear something like the image below:
		  		
		  		<imagedata fileref="images/newStreamWizard1.png" width="550px" scalefit="1"/>
		  	</para>
		  	<para>
		  		Enter a name and a description for your new Stream, and click "Next" to proceed to the next page of the
		  		New Stream Wizard.  The second page will appear something like the image below:
		  		
		  		<imagedata fileref="images/newStreamWizard2.png" width="550px" scalefit="1"/>
		  		
		  	</para>
		  	<para>
		  		
		  		Select the types of content you wish to appear in your new stream (Ctrl+Click to select multiple items)
		  		and click "Next" to go to the next page of the New Stream Wizard. The third page will appear something 
		  		like the image below:
		  		
		  		<imagedata fileref="images/newStreamWizard3.png" width="550px" scalefit="1"/>
		  	</para>
		  	
		  	<para>
		  	
		  		Select the users whose updates you wish to appear in your new stream  and click "Next" to go to the 
		  		next page of the New Stream Wizard. The fourth page will appear something  like the image below:
		  	
		  		<imagedata fileref="images/newStreamWizard4.png" width="550px" scalefit="1"/>
		  	</para>
		  	
		  	<para>
		  		Select the User Lists that contain users whose updates you wish to appear in your new stream  and click "Next" to go to the 
		  		next page of the New Stream Wizard. The fifth page will appear something  like the image below:

		  	
		  		<imagedata fileref="images/newStreamWizard5.png" width="550px" scalefit="1"/>
		  	</para>
		  	
		  	<para>
		  		Select the Groups whose updates you wish to appear in your new stream  and click "Next" to go to the 
		  		next page of the New Stream Wizard. The sixth page will appear something  like the image below:
		  		<imagedata fileref="images/newStreamWizard6.png" width="550px" scalefit="1"/>
		  	</para>
		  	
		  	<para>
		  		Select the Subscriptions whose content you wish to appear in your new stream  and click "Finish" to complete
		  		the New Stream Wizard. This will return you to the "Manage Streams" page, and you will see your new
		  		Stream listed along with the others. 
		  		<imagedata fileref="images/newStreamWizard7.png" width="550px" scalefit="1"/>
		  	</para>
		  	
		  	
		</section>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="userProfileChapter" xreflabel="User Profile">
		<title>Your User Profile</title>
		<section id="userProfileSection1">
			<title>Basics</title>
			<para>
				Coming soon...
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="userProfileSection2">
		    <title>Advanced</title>
		    <para>Coming Soon...</para>
		</section>

	</chapter>


	<chapter id="friendsFollowersChapter" xreflabel="Friends &amp; Followers">
		<title>Friends &amp; Followers</title>
		<section id="friendsFollowersSection1">
			<title>Basics</title>
			<para>
				Coming soon...
			</para>
		</section>
	
		<section id="friendsFollowersSection2">
		    <title>Advanced</title>
		    <para>Coming Soon...</para>
		</section>
	
	</chapter>
	
	
	<chapter id="subscriptionsChapter" xreflabel="Subscriptions">
		<title>Subscriptions</title>
		<section id="subscriptionsSection1">
			<title>Basics</title>
			<para>
				Coming soon...
			</para>
		</section>		
		
		<section id="subscriptionsSection2">
		    <title>Advanced</title>
		    <para>Coming Soon...</para>
		</section>
		
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="neddickIntegrationChapter" xreflabel="Neddick Integration">
		<title>Neddick Integration</title>
		<section id="neddickIntegrationSection1">
			<title>Basics</title>
			<para>
				Coming soon...
			</para>
		</section>		
		
		<section id="neddickIntegraionSection2">
		    <title>Advanced</title>
		    <para>Coming Soon...</para>
		</section>
		
	</chapter>
	
</book>
