<?xml version="1.0" ?>
                   
<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
		version="5.0">
	<info>
      	<title>Quoddy Help</title>
		<author>
        	<personname>
        		<firstname>Phillip</firstname>
        		<surname>Rhodes</surname>
        	</personname>
		</author>
      	<copyright>
      		<year>2013</year>
      		<holder>Fogbeam Labs</holder>
      	</copyright>
	</info>	
	<chapter>
		
		<title>Introduction to Quoddy</title>
				
		<para>
			Quoddy is an Open Source Enterprise Social Network, which shares common "look and feel" elements, 
			and substantial functionality, with consumer facing Social Networks like 
			Facebook or Google+ as well as proprietary Enterprise Social Network products 
			like the products from Jive Software and Yammer among others.   But unlike
			consumer Social Networks, Quoddy is intended for organizational use and therefore has 
			capabilities which make it uniquely suited to provide the social fabric to 
			support organizational knowledge sharing, knowledge transfer, collaboration and 
			decision support.
		</para>

      	<section>
      	
      		<title>The Activity Stream</title>
			<para> The Activity Stream is the central element of the Quoddy interface.  The Activity Stream
			takes up the right hand side of the main page in Quoddy, and displays Status Updates
			from other users, Business Events from backend systems, Calendar Events from calendaring
			/ groupware systems, User Tasks from BPM / workflow systems, User activity events from external
			systems, Document links from Document Management Systems, and other events of interest to you, based on
			the users you friend/follow, groups you join, and the subscriptions you define. 
			</para>
	   		<para>
	   			Since Users do not necessarily want to see all content all the time, Quoddy has a concept known as
	   			Stream Definitions.  A User creates a Stream Definition to collect a related group of Users, User Lists, Groups
	   			and Subscriptions, and batch that content together.  When a User has multiple Stream Definitions, a simple
	   			dropdown menu allows the User to toggle which collection is rendered into the main Activity Stream at
	   			any given time.  
	   		</para>
	   	</section>		
		
		<section>
      	
      		<title>Friends &amp; Followers</title>
			<para> Adding another User as a "Friend" requires that User's approval and creates a two way
			connection between the two Users.  Following a User creates a one-way connection and does not
			require approval from the User being followed. </para>

	   	
	   	</section>
		
		<section>
      	
      		<title> User Lists &amp; Groups</title>
			<para> User Lists allow a User to group related people together, and quickly
			filter their Activity Stream down to only updates from those Users.  A User
			can have multiple such groups, and a simple dropdown menu allows the User to select
			the active User List at any time.</para>
	   		<para>
	   			Groups support multi-user collaboration around a given topic, interest, project, or other
	   			unifying concept.  Users may search for Groups which are of interest to them, join those
	   			Groups, and then share content with, and recieve status updates from, those Groups.  A User
	   			may join many Groups, and a simple dropdown menu allows the User to select which Group's content
	   			they wish to view at any given time.
	   		</para>
	   	</section>

		<section>
      	
      		<title>Subscriptions</title>
			<para> Perhaps the most powerful and important feature in Quoddy, subscriptions
			allow Users to register interest in various kinds of content from both within
			their organization, and from outside the organiation, and then have that content
			delivered straight to their Activity Stream.  </para>
	   		<para>
	   			More to come...
	   		</para>
	   	</section>
		
	</chapter>

	<chapter>
		<title>Using the Activity Stream</title>
		<section>
			<para>
				Coming soon...
			</para>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Your User Profile</title>
		<section>
			<para>
				Coming soon...
			</para>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Friends &amp; Followers</title>
		<section>
			<para>
				Coming soon...
			</para>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Subscriptions</title>
		<section>
			<para>
				Coming soon...
			</para>
		</section>		
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Neddick</title>
		<section>
			<para>
				Coming soon...
			</para>
		</section>		
	</chapter>
	
</book>
